One will fall.
Godzilla vs. Kong is a action, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Adam Wingard.
In a time when monsters walk the Earth, humanity’s fight for its future sets Godzilla and Kong on a collision course that
will see the two most powerful forces of nature on the planet collide in a spectacular battle for the ages.
Nathan Lind, played by Alexander Skarsgård.
Ilene Andrews, played by Rebecca Hall.
Jia, played by Kaylee Hottle.
Bernie Hayes, played by Brian Tyree Henry.
Madison Russell, played by Millie Bobby Brown.
Josh Valentine, played by Julian Dennison.
Godzilla vs.
Kong is a 2021 American monster film directed by Adam Wingard.
Produced by Legendary Pictures and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, it is a sequel to Kong: Skull Island (2017) and Godzilla: King of the
Monsters (2019), and is the fourth film in the Monsterverse.
It is also the 36th film in the Godzilla franchise, the 12th film in the King Kong franchise, and
the fourth Godzilla film to be completely produced by an American film studio.
The film stars Alexander Skarsgård, Millie Bobby Brown, Rebecca Hall, Brian Tyree Henry, Shun
Oguri, Eiza González, Julian Dennison, Lance Reddick, Kyle Chandler, and Demián Bichir.
Brown and Chandler reprise their roles from the previous Godzilla film.
In the film, Kong clashes with Godzilla after the Monarch organization moves the ape from Skull Island to the Hollow Earth, homeworld of the
monsters known as "Titans", and to retrieve a power source for a secret weapon intended to stop Godzilla's mysterious attacks.
The project was announced in October 2015 when Legendary Pictures declared plans
for a shared cinematic universe between Godzilla and King Kong.
The film's writers' room was assembled in March 2017, and
Wingard was announced as the director in May 2017.
Principal photography began in November 2018 in Hawaii,
Australia, and Hong Kong, and wrapped in April 2019.
After being delayed from a November 2020 release date due
to the COVID-19 pandemic, Godzilla vs.
Kong was theatrically released internationally on March 24, 2021, and in the United
States on March 31, where it was released on HBO Max simultaneously.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for the visual
effects and action sequences, but criticism towards the human characters.
It broke several pandemic box office records, and grossed $470 million worldwide, against a production budget between
$155–200 million and a break-even point of $330 million, making it the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2021.
The film was a streaming hit, becoming the most successful launch title in
HBO Max's history until it was overtaken by Mortal Kombat.
A sequel, Godzilla x Kong: The New Empire, also directed by
Wingard, was released on March 29, 2024.
The film explores themes of giant monster, dinosaur,
creature feature, kaiju, sign languages.
The tone is thought_provoking.